newyorkmetro.com 2008-06-02

# New York Magazine - Nymag.com - Privacy Policy

_Amended as of October 3, 2007_ **

Click below for specific information about:

**  
Website Membership Eligibility and Participation  
Types of Information Collected and Purpose  
Use and Collection of Information by Operational Providers  
Disclosure to Third Parties  
Cookies and Tracking Devices  
How to Add, Delete or Change Information  
Third Party Advertising  
Third Party Cookies  
Our Security Procedures   
Children's Privacy Policy  
Terms of Usage Agreement

Safeguarding your privacy is very important to us. We take seriously the collection of any personally identifiable information and personal contact information ("personal information") from our visitors and are committed to protecting each visitor's privacy in accordance with these policies. We use the term "visitors" to include registered members of our website communities and any other person that accesses our websites at any point for any amount of time, unless designated otherwise. Please carefully review our information collection practices and privacy protections below. 

**Who We Are And How To Reach Us**

New York Media LLC, doing business in the State of New York as New York Media (DE) LLC owns and operates the New York Magazine website ("NYMag.com"). NYMag.com is a division of New York Media LLC, doing business in the State of New York as New York Media (DE) LLC and is the only operator of this website. You may contact us directly if you have any questions regarding the content and material on our website or if you have any questions about our privacy policies. Please contact our Privacy Officer at:

Michael Silberman   
Online General Manager  
NewYorkMagazine.com   
75 Varick Street  
New York, NY 10013  
Phone: (212) 508-0803  
E-mail: michael.silberman@newyorkmag.com

Submit a Comment

**Website Membership and Participation Eligibility**

Parts of our website may require that you be thirteen (13) years of age or older to participate and/or be a member and receive membership benefits, and you must be eighteen (18) years of age or older to participate in our A-List Invitations. We may conduct other contests, sweepstakes and/or special events over our site. To participate in these events, you must meet the designated minimum age requirements (for example, twenty-one (21) years of age or older) for the specific event. Please see our Terms of Usage Agreement for additional information on membership and/or participation on our website. 

**Collection of Personal Information**

We provide various informative, educational, and entertaining features as part of this website. To operate these features, we collect certain non-personal and personal information from our visitors for specific purposes. For website activities that request personal information, you agree to provide accurate and current information about yourself. Your membership and/or participation in our website activities will be canceled without notice if at any time we discover that you provide false information, or violate any term of our Privacy Policy or our Terms of Usage Agreement. We may retain personal information for an indefinite amount of time to preserve our database and to comply with various federal and state laws. 

**Registration for Participation in Website Activities and Services**

**Use and Collection of Information by Nymag.com**

To participate as a member of our website, or in online activities, special events, contests, sweepstakes or Interactive Areas ("Interactive Areas" include chat rooms, bulletin boards, message boards or auditoriums, article or blog comment areas, SMS text messaging, mobile alerts, and mobile e-mail updates), you may be required to provide personally identifiable information such as your name, home and e-mail addresses, telephone number, birth date and gender ("personal information"). We may also survey visitors about various topics, including local events and experiences, television viewing preferences and how we can improve our website and services. Response to our surveys is entirely voluntary. 

We offer SMS text message mobile alerts and mobile e-mail updates as a text messaging/mobile e-mail service for our restaurant and bar listings. We do not collect the sender's e-mail or telephone number on this feature. 

We collect personal information for several important purposes, including to operate our membership base, protect the security of our visitors and the site, improve our service and website, distribute our newsletters, notify the winners of our contests and sweepstakes, allow participation in specified activities or Interactive Areas and for future marketing and/or promotional use about our program service or website. We may also offer an "Email This” feature that allows visitors to e-mail a link to another person to inform them about the NYMag.com site and our features. We do not collect the sender's or the recipient's e-mail information on this feature. 

We may also offer an “Email Album” feature that allows members to share their fashion albums with others. If you e-mail your fashion albums to others, the emailed albums will automatically be made public for anyone to access. You can also choose to make your albums private so only you can access them. We do not collect the sender’s e-mail information on this feature. 

The only personal information this website obtains about you is information voluntarily provided by you through our website. This means that a person can visit our website and navigate through the site without giving us personal information. This website does not collect additional personal information about individual visitors or members from other sources. To gauge the effectiveness of our website, we may collect non-personal information about our members and visitors, such as Internet server and browser identification, the Internet service provider, clickstream information, the web page from which a person enters our site, webpages visited, duration of visit and domain type. This information does not reveal a visitor's personal identity.

We may produce certain contests, sweepstakes and special events with the support of affiliated or non-affiliated sponsors and/or promotional partners. The personal information collected by our website in conjunction with such events may also be used for the marketing of additional services and events by NYMag.com and/or its promotional partners and sponsors beyond the contest, sweepstakes and/or special event. Depending on the event, visitors will be able to either grant their approval on how their personal information will be used before it is collected ("opt-in"), or choose to deny use of their information for additional purposes ("opt-out"). For each contest, sweepstakes, and/or special event, we will post on the website applicable rules for the event, and if necessary, post any supplemental terms and conditions or privacy provisions. To the extent there is a conflict between those privacy provisions and this policy, the privacy provisions for the specific event will govern. 

**Use and Collection of Information by Operational Providers**

For the convenience of our visitors, we may provide the opportunity to purchase certain goods, merchandise and services through this website (including, without limitation, on-line personals services). Companies other than NYMag.com, its parents, partners, affiliates or subsidiaries may handle some of these transactions. We call these companies that conduct our e-commerce operations, order fulfillment and/or contract services "operational providers." If you choose to use these optional services, our operational providers will request your personal information to fulfill your order or request. The voluntary submission of your personal information to these operational providers, including your order or request, will be governed by the specific provider's terms of usage and privacy policies. To facilitate an order or request, we may share your personal information with the provider. The operational provider may also share your personal information with us. We will store this information in our membership database. In most instances, we request that our operational providers adhere to the provisions in NYMag.com's Privacy Policy and that such providers only share visitors' personal information with NYMag.com, unless necessary to complete a visitor's request or order. We also request that these providers only use the personal information for the purpose of conducting the sale or fulfilling the requested service or order. However, you must read an operational providers privacy policy to determine the extent of use and disclosure of your personal information collected online. NYMag.com, its parents, affiliates and subsidiaries are not responsible for the collection, use and disclosure practices of operational providers, nor is the NYMag.com family responsible or liable for the products or services provided by operational providers. 

** ****Our Policy on Disclosing Your Information to Parties Other than New York Magazine**

We only share or disclose your personal information with companies other than NYMag.com when it is required by law, disclosure is necessary to operate the website or certain website services, to protect the safety of our visitors, employees or property and/or when disclosure is consistent with NYMag.com's practices for services that are similarly provided offline. The website may offer you the opportunity to give user reviews, ratings and comments for restaurants, hotels, bars, events, articles or other items, or to participate in Interactive Areas. Your member name may appear next to your user reviews, ratings, comments or other postings or participation in Interactive Areas on the website. Your member name may also appear on a member profile section of the website. We may also use and disclose your member name and reviews and ratings in any other manner in accordance with the Terms of Usage Agreement.

NYMag.com is a division of New York Media LLC, doing business in the State of New York as New York Media (DE) LLC. We may in the future share personal information with our parents, partners, affiliates or other entities for other purposes. If we decide to enter into such sharing arrangements, we will disclose to our registered members and in this Privacy Policy the name of the entity(s) that we will share information with, what type of personal information will be shared, how the information will be used, and how to contact us if you do not want us to share your personal information ("opt-out"). We may conduct joint activities with members of the NYMag.com family; however, we will not share individual visitors' personal information with these entities unless we provide notice in this Privacy Policy.

When visitors send an e-mail to us, we will protect your e-mail address and other personal contact information. However, we may disclose the content of your e-mail to other persons. Please see our Terms of Usage Agreement. We may share your personal information with our operational providers or those persons, companies or agents who provide support for the internal operations of the website, such as contest fulfillment services, maintenance and technical services, and e-commerce and auction contractors. If you are purchasing goods, merchandise or services on this website and use a credit card to complete the transaction, our operational providers may share your personal information and credit card number with a ticket agent, a credit card processing and/or a shipping/fulfillment company in order to complete your order.

We may collect and provide aggregate information about our visitors to our advertisers, sponsors, promotional partners, and affiliates, such as how many persons visited a particular page or activity, the average age of our visitors on the site or page, or the likes and dislikes of our visitors, but this information does not include personal information about any individual visitor. We may obtain geographic information such as zip code clustering from other sources, but this aggregate information will not reveal any personal information about a specific visitor. 

******Use of Cookies and Tracking Devices**

This site uses cookies or other tracking devices. A cookie is a small data file that contains a unique identification number that a website places on your hard drive when you visit a site. The "cookie" is able to store information such as data about your computer, the type of browser you use, and how many times your computer visits a certain site. Cookies do not allow the website to access personal information that you haven't already provided. Cookies enable us to track how often visitors are visiting our website and specific pages, the number of entries in specific events, the estimated audience size for sponsors and advertisers, and user preferences. You can refuse to use cookies by turning them off in your browser. Please contact your software manufacturer for questions on how to disable your cookies. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use most of this site. However, you may find that some areas on the website will be slower, or may not function at all, and you may not be able to participate in certain activities such as contests or sweepstakes if the cookies are disabled. 

This site uses clear GIFs [Graphics Interchange Formats] (also known as pixel tags, web beacons or web bugs). A clear GIF is a tiny line of code only 1 by 1 pixel in size that is programmed to collect certain information about a visit to a particular website. We use GIFs to gather non-personal, aggregate information on visits to our website, track usage of website links and assist with registration and log-on features, including chat rooms and e-mail. We do not disclose personal information that may be linked to our GIF collection practices to third parties. Other websites may also use clear GIFs. NYMag.com, its parents and subsidiaries are not responsible for the use of clear GIFs by other website operators. Visitor's must review other website operators' privacy policies to determine the type and extent of tracking devices used. 

**Use and Collection of Information by Advertisers and Sponsors**

We use a third-party advertising company to serve ads when you visit our site. This advertising company may collect and use information (not including your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number) about your visits to our site and other websites not owned and operated by NYMag.com, and may also combine this information with other data about your purchases and interests from other online and offline sources, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. In addition, we may share non-personal website usage information about visitors to this site with this company for the purpose of managing and targeting advertisements and for market research analysis on our site and other sites. For these purposes, NYMag.com and our third party advertising company may note some of the pages you visit on our site through the use of pixel tags (also called clear GIFs). In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your computer. If you would like more information about the collection, use and disclosure practices of this third party advertising company and to know your choices about not having this information used by this company, [click here.](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/corporate/privacy/privacy/default.asp?asp_object_1=&)

Our website may post banner ads and other forms of advertisements, and/or links to the websites of affiliate entities or of advertisers or sponsors which are companies that are not owned or operated by NYMag.com, its parents, affiliates or subsidiaries. These entities may independently solicit and collect personal information, or send their own cookies to our visitors. Please be advised that when you link to or visit an advertiser's or sponsor's website, we may frame the site with our website logo; however, you will be subject to the privacy policy and terms of usage agreement of that website operator. NYMag.com, its parents, affiliates or subsidiaries will not be responsible for advertiser or sponsor ads and/or links or the content, activities, information collection, use and disclosure practices of the websites of advertisers and sponsors. 

We may also provide co-branded services or promotions with certain sponsors or other entities. As a part of these services or promotions, we may request the submission of your personal information over our website for participation and/or registration. We may also share your information with the sponsor or entity assisting with the service or promotion to fulfill your request. If the co-sponsor or other entity collects your personal information, they may also share your information with us. 

**Third Party Advertising**

The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to you by DoubleClick, our Web advertising partner. Information about your visits to this site, such as number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address, or other personal information), is used to serve ads to you. For more information about DoubleClick, cookies, and how to "opt-out", please [click here](http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy). 

**Third Party Cookies**

In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser.

**Our Security Procedures**

We require our employees to protect the privacy of all information collected over our website. Only employees and supervisors with specific authorization have access to databases containing visitors' personal information. The databases are protected in a secure facility. Credit card information is transmitted via encrypted technology. If we decide to share visitor information with other members of the NYMag.com family, the receiving entity will also maintain the security and integrity of personal information collected over our website. That said, it is not possible to guarantee the security or integrity of information you disclose online since a sufficiently powerful attack from an unauthorized third party, however unlikely, could compromise your data.

For the convenience of our visitors, we may offer a list of helpful website links provided by other entities and/or persons. NYMag.com does not endorse or recommend, nor is it liable for, the products or services of any websites not owned or operated by NYMag.com. When you visit other websites you will also be subject to the privacy policies and terms of usage agreements, if any, of that website operator. 

**Notification of Changes in the Privacy Policy**

We will review our security measures and Privacy Policy on a periodic basis, and we may modify our policies as NYMag.com deems appropriate. We may also change or update our Privacy Policy if we add new services or features and will post these changes in this policy. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy on a regular basis. 

**CHILDREN'S PRIVACY POLICY**

NYMag.com respects the privacy of your child and we want to share with you our policies regarding children under the age of thirteen (13). We have developed this site to appeal to visitors over the age of thirteen (13). Although visitors of all ages may navigate through our website, we do not knowingly collect personal information from persons under the age of thirteen (13). If upon notification by a parent or guardian, or discovery by other means, that a child under thirteen (13) has improperly registered on this site by using false information, we will immediately cancel the child's membership and/or participation, and delete the child's personally identifiable information, member name and password from our records.

If we decide to request information from children, we will require verifiable parental consent before we collect any personal information from children under thirteen (13) years of age, except in the following circumstances allowed by law: 

  * To provide notice and get consent from a parent or guardian;
  * To respond to a one-time request from a child, after which we will immediately delete the child's information;
  * To fulfill a child's request for a subscription to a online newspaper, magazine or specific information on a regular basis and we will notify the parent or guardian before we contact the child again;
  * To protect the safety of a child who is participating on this site; and
  * To protect the security or integrity of the site, take precautions against liability, respond to a validly executed subpoena or warrant from law enforcement, or if permitted under other provisions of law. 

**Guidelines for Parents**

By taking responsibility for your children's online computer use, parents can greatly minimize any potential risks for being online. The best way to assure that your children are having positive online experiences is to stay in touch with what they are doing. One way to do this is to spend time with your children while they are online. Have them show you what they are doing and ask them to teach you how to access the services. 

While children and teenagers need a certain amount of privacy, they also need parental involvement and supervision in their daily lives. The same general parenting skills that apply to the "real world" also apply while online. 

**_Make it a family rule to:_**

  * Never give out identifying information-home address, school name, or telephone number — in a public message such as chat or bulletin boards, and be sure you're dealing with someone that both you and your child know and trust before giving it out via email. Think carefully before revealing any personal information such as age, marital status, or financial information. Consider using a pseudonym or unlisting your child's name if your service allows it.
  * Get to know the services your child uses. If you don't know how to log on, get your child to show you. Find out what types of information it offers, and whether there are ways for parents to block out objectionable material.
  * Never allow a child to arrange a face-to-face meeting with another computer user without parental permission. If a meeting is arranged, make the first one in a public spot, and be sure to accompany your child.
  * Never respond to messages or bulletin board items that are suggestive, obscene, belligerent, threatening, or make you feel uncomfortable. Encourage your children to tell you if they encounter such messages. If you or your child receives a message that is harassing, of a sexual nature, or threatening, forward a copy of the message to your service provider and ask for their assistance.
  * Should you become aware of the transmission, use, or viewing of child pornography while online, immediately report this to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children by calling 1-800-843-5678. You should also notify your online service. Remember that people online may not be who they seem. Because you can't see or even hear the person it would be easy for someone to misrepresent him-or herself. Thus, someone indicating that "she" is a "12 year-old girl" could in reality be a 40-year-old man. 
  * Remember that everything you read online may not be true. Any offer that's "too good to be true" probably is. Be very careful about any offers that involve your coming to a meeting or having someone visit your house. 
  * Set reasonable rules and guidelines for computer use by your children. Discuss these rules and post them near the computer as a reminder. Remember to monitor their compliance with these rules, especially when it comes to the amount of time your children spend on the computer. A child or teenager's excessive use of online services or bulletin boards, especially late at night, may be a clue that there is a potential problem. Remember that personal computers and online services should not be used as electronic babysitters. Be sure to make this a family activity. Consider keeping the computer in a family room rather than the child's bedroom. Get to know their "online friends" just as you get to know all of their other friends. 

Please do not hesitate to contact us if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy. 

_Contact us at:_ 75 Varick Street , 4th Floor, New York, New York 10013   
_Phone:_ (212) 508-0803  
_E-mail:_ michael.silberman@newyorkmag.com

Thank you for visiting!
